Now that we've seen a quick glimpse at
والآن بعد أن اطلعنا على لمحة سريعة عن
the plots that are possible for a number of scenarios,
المخططات التي تكون ممكنة لعدد من السيناريوهات،
let's go through a quick example to see the difference
دعونا نطلع على مثال سريع لمعرفة الاختلافات
and the questions we can answer using these plots.
والأسئلة التي يمكننا الإجابة عنها باستخدام هذه المخططات.
Consider I run a blog and I want to understand traffic on the blog.
فكروا في تشغيل مدونة ورغبتي في فهم عدد الزيارات للمدونة.
For simplicity, let's just use 12 months worth of traffic.
لتبسيط الأمر، دعونا نستخدم قيم عدد الزيارات في 12 شهرًا.
If we wanted to know which month we had the most traffic,
إذا أردنا معرفة أي شهر يكون فيه أكبر عدد من الزيارات،
the best plot would be a bar chart or Pareto chart,
فإن أفضل مخطط هو مخطط شريطي أو مخطط باريتو،
as this would put the months in order from highest to lowest traffic.
لأن هذا من شأنه أن يضع الأشهر بالترتيب من الأعلى إلى الأقل من حيث عدد الزيارات.
Each bar is the amount of traffic for a particular month.
يمثل كل شريط مقدار عدد الزيارات لشهر معين.
It is pretty easy to see that November had the highest amount of traffic.
من السهل جدًا رؤية أن شهر نوفمبر يحتوي على أكبر مقدار من عدد الزيارات.
If we wanted to know if traffic was increasing over time,
إذا أردنا معرفة ما إذا كانت الزيارات تتزايد بمرور الوقت،
the best chart would be a line chart.
فسيكون أفضل مخطط هو المخطط الخطي.
The same information is present here,
تظهر المعلومات نفسها هنا،
but it's easier to see that overall traffic appears to be
ولكن من الأسهل رؤية أن إجمالي عدد الزيارات يبدو
increasing just from the changing in the bars to a line.
أنه يتزايد من التغير في الأشرطة إلى خط فقط.
If we had multiple years of data,
إذا كانت لدينا بيانات متعددة لعدة سنوات،
the line chart would also assist in identifying if
فسيساعد المخطط الخطي أيضًا في تحديد
particular months had higher or lower traffic than others.
ما إذا كانت أشهر معينة قد تحتوي على عدد زيارات أعلى أو أقل من غيرها.
Maybe September would always be a low,
ربما يحتوي شهر سبتمبر على أقل نسبة دائمًا،
and November would always be higher than the other months in the year.
ودائمًا ما يحتوي شهر نوفمبر على نسبة أعلى من الأشهر الأخرى في العام.
What if we had multiple years worth of data and we wanted
ماذا لو كان لدينا بيانات لسنوات متعددة وأردنا
to know what the distribution of the number of visitors looked like.
معرفة شكل توزيع عدد الزوار.
How frequently were there more than 2,000 visitors in a month?
ما عدد المرات التي كان فيها أكثر من 2000 زائر في الشهر؟
What was the most common number of visitors?
ما عدد الزائرين الأكثر شيوعًا؟
From either the bar or the line chart,
قد يصعب معرفة ذلك سواء كان من المخطط الشريطي
this can be tough to tell.
أو المخطط الخطي.
And neither of these questions are aimed at understanding the time component.
ولا يهدف أيٌّ من هذه الأسئلة إلى فهم مكون الوقت.
We're interested in specifically looking at the count.
نحن مهتمون بالاطلاع على العدد تحديدًا.
A histogram of the number of visitors looks like this,
يشبه الرسم البياني لعدد الزائرين ذلك،
and it's useful for better understanding the typical number of visitors in a month.
كما أنه مفيد لتحسين فهم العدد المعتاد للزائرين خلال شهر.
And the height of the bars tells us how often a certain number of visitors has occurred.
ويبلغنا ارتفاع الأشرطة بمدى تكرار عدد معين من الزوار.
Is seeing 500 visitors on the blog a rare occurrence?
ألا ترون أن وجود 500 زائر على المدونة أمر نادر الحدوث؟
We can quickly see that 500 is rare.
سريعًا ما نعرف أن الرقم 500 أمر نادر.
We can see that there are always more than 200 visitors,
ويمكننا رؤية أن دائمًا ما يكون هناك أكثر من 200 زائر،
but there are rarely more than 1,200 visitors.
لكن نادرًا ما يكون هناك أكثر من 1200 زائر.
The most common number of visitors is between 325 and 450.
يتراوح عدد الزائرين الأكثر شيوعًا ما بين 325 و450 زائرًا.
These observations would have been much more difficult to see on those earlier plots.
كان من الصعب جدًا رؤية هذه الملاحظات على المخططات السابقة.
In the instructor notes below,
في ملاحظات المعلم أدناه،
I've provided a link to the Google Sheets data and
لقد أرفقت رابطًا بيانات Google Sheets
charts that were used for creating the visuals in this presentation.
ومخططاتها التي استخدمناها لإنشاء العناصر المرئية في هذا العرض التقديمي.
Again, because of the time component in the data,
ومرة أخرى، نظرًا لمكون الوقت في البيانات،
the line chart is probably best,
قد يكون المخطط الخطي أفضل،
but it ultimately depends on the message that you want to convey.
لكنه يعتمد في النهاية على الرسالة التي تريدون نقلها.
Using the same data,
باستخدام البيانات نفسها،
we just found three ways to present the data.
وجدنا ثلاث طرق لتقديم البيانات فقط.
The right way to visualize the data is in the way
الطريقة الصحيحة لتصور البيانات هي
that best helps you answer your question.
الطريقة المثلى التي تساعدكم في الإجابة عن سؤالكم.